Contact

davonnrdutton@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/davonn-dutton-ms-hcm-rn-1848a352 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Advanced Cardiovascular Life Support Provider Critical Care Basic Life Support Provider

Certifications

Scrum Fundamentals Certified (SFC)

Davonn Dutton, MS-HCM, RN

Quality Coordinator RN

Tomball, Texas

Summary

Experienced Registered Nurse with a demonstrated history of working in the local and travel nursing industry. Skilled in Medical Devices, JCAHO, Vital Signs, Intensive Care, and Team Building. Strong healthcare services professional with a MS focused in Healthcare Management from the University of New Orleans.

Experience

HCA Healthcare
Quality Coordinator
June 2018 - Present (2 years 2 months)
Tomball, Texas

Medical Staffing Network
Registered Nurse
February 2013 - Present (7 years 6 months)
Houston, Texas

LSU Health Sciences Center

1 year 10 months

Registered Nurse

October 2011 - February 2013 (1 year 5 months)

- •Demonstrates knowledge and proper technique in airway management
- •Administers blood products using proper procedure
- •Prepares and assist physician in various medical therapies
- •Exhibits high degree of competence in code management
- •Demonstrates knowledge of diagnostic tests and obtains specimens as orders
- •Provides wound management and monitors drainage devices as appropriate
- •Develops ability to anticipate changes in patient condition and responds appropriately
- Understands admit and discharge nursing
- •Demonstrates knowledge of ventilators, cardiac monitors, A-line and CVP
- •Follows infusion protocols of department etc

Nurse Tech

May 2011 - October 2011 (6 months)

- •Performs basic duties related to the care of the patients
- •Obtains and records vital signs; observes for and reports any acute change in the patient's status
- Accurately measures and records I&O
- Assists nurses and physicians as needed/requested
- •Adheres to the Trauma ICU, Division of Nursing, MCLNO and Joint Commission of Accreditation of Hospital Organizations (JCAHO) policies, performance and practice standards

Care Concepts

Intake Coordinator

January 2010 - September 2010 (9 months)

Processing all incoming patient orders (Supplies, equipment, other)

- •Verifying prescription, eligibility, benefits and initial data entry of information based on established policies and procedures
- Providing notification of denial to patient and Care Coordinator
- Counseling patient of alternative payment option in the event of denials
- •Advising patients of their rights and responsibilities, including financial responsibilities, including financial responsibility for co-payments and zero balances
- •Prepare all necessary paperwork for DME billing (I-CD 9 codes, Dx codes, etc)
- Superior to Care Coordinator and delivery staff

Education

University of Louisiana at Lafayette

BSN, Nursing · (2013 - 2020)

Our Lady of the Lake College

Associate of Science (A.S.), Registered Nursing/Registered Nurse · (2010 - 2011)

University of New Orleans

Master of Science (MS), Health/Health Care Administration/ Management · (2008 - 2009)

Nicholls State University

Bachelor of Science (BS), Allied Health and Professional Practice · (2004 - 2008)